Edward R. Murrow Papers MS025
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Audiotapes and other media, 1939 -- 1974; MS025.005; 56.1 Linear Feet; 19 Audiovisual Object(s); 592 Digital Object(s)
  - This I Believe (10" Audiotape Reels), 1951 -- 1954; MS025.005.004; 16 Audiovisual Object(s); 587 Digital Object(s)
    - This I Believe, XTV18547, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00005 (Reel 5)
      - That Little, Inner Voice, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00005.00003; Pons, Lily (Reel 5)
        Stage fright; Self-Consciousness (Awareness); Self-actualization (Psychology); Women singers; Self-culture; Performance artists; Music; Singing; Humility; audio tape; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.)
    - This I Believe, XTV18548, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00006 (Reel 5)
      10" Reel. Job#116096. Written on box "1,3,4". Written on reel but crossed off "Joan of Arc Prologue"
      - This I Believe, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00006.00001; Brown, Dale (Reel 5)
        Dale Brown describes his belief that he must repay the debt he owes to his community through service to others in the community, as well as his belief that we must strive for tolerance, limiting anger and listening to others.
        Social Networks; Good and evil; Religious life; Gratitude; Toleration; Altruism; Brotherliness; Listening; audio tape; National City Bank of Cleveland
      - This I Believe, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00006.00002; MacNeice, Louis (Reel 5)
        Louis MacNeice defines beliefs as statements of personal preference, and describes his belief that the world can avoid anarchism because people share many of the same preferences, including the desire to build an orderly society.
        Ethical relativism; Value; Purpose; Reason; Questioning; audio tape
      - This I Believe, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00006.00003; West, Guy A. (Guy Ashley) (Reel 5)
        Guy West recounts how he first became aware of the immense size of the universe, and describes his beliefs in a God who designed and provides purpose for that universe.
        Purpose; Universe; Science; Intelligent design (Teleology); Meaning (philosophy); audio tape; California State University, Sacramento
      - This I Believe, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00006.00004; McKinney, Howard (Reel 5)
        Howard McKinney describes growing up in an urban city (Pittsburgh) and explains that, because of the influence of a Sunday School teacher he directed his life away from crime, he feels compelled to offer similar opportunities to Pittsburgh's youth today.
        YouthServices for; Social problems; Urban youth; Mentoring; Religious life; Altruism; audio tape; Hill City (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
    - This I Believe, XTV18550, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00007 (Reel 5)
      10" Reel. Job#116096.
      - The Roots of Our Progress, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00007.00001; Hoover, Herbert (Reel 5)
        President Hoover describes the importance of religious faith in life, science, and politics. A duplicate of this essay is on reel XTV-16923 (Box 002).
        Civil rights; Faith; Materialism; Avarice; Progress; Science; Truth; Religion; Intelligent design (Teleology); Natural lawReligious aspects; audio tape
      - This I Believe, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00007.00002; Thomas, Benjamin Platt (Reel 5)
        Benjamin Thomas describes how his study of Abraham Lincoln helped him believe that there is a universal struggle between good and evil, and that acknowledging our own imperfections helps us to be tolerant of others.
        Intelligent design (Teleology); Lincoln, Abraham 1809-1865; UncertaintyReligious aspects; Good and evil; Perfection; Toleration; Equality; audio tape; Abraham Lincoln Association (Springfield, Ill.)
      - This I Believe, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00007.00003; O'Leary, Thomas V. (Reel 5)
        Thomas O Leary describes stories of human kindness, and his belief that working in newspapers is a way to bring the truth to light.
        Truth; Altruism; Kindness; Brotherliness; Faith; Progress; Justice; audio tape; Scranton times (Scranton, Pa.: 1891: Daily)
      - This I Believe, 1952-11-21; MS025.005.004.005.00007.00004; Danforth, William H. (William Henry) (Reel 5)
        William Danforth describes how, when he was a sickly farm boy, his school teacher challenged him to live healthily; from that, Danforth developed a life philosophy to stand tall (through exercise and healthy eating habits), think tall (through education), smile tall (through friendliness and kindness) and live tall (through character development).
        Self-culture; Character; Diet; Exercise; Education; Kindness; Responsibility; Altruism; Integrity; audio tape; Ralston Purina Company
    - This I Believe, XTV18551, MS025.005.004.005.00008 (Reel 5)
      10" Reel. Job#116096. "2,3,4" written on box. No date is available for this reel.
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00008.00001; Menzies, P. K. (Reel 5)
        P. K. Menzies describes his belief in the physician's responsibility to treat his patients with respect and dignity, and explains how his study of the intricate workings of the human body formed his belief that the universe must have been designed by a "supreme architect."
        Intelligent design (Teleology); Respect; Dignity; Medicine; Self-actualization (Psychology); Equality; Kindness; Compassion; audio tape; Syracuse University. College of Medicine
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00008.00002; Watson, Lucile (Reel 5)
        Lucile Watson recounts her childhood discovery of the knowledge that she could change herself for the better, and, after successes with simple things such as maintaining her hair and quitting nail-biting, she developed a philosophy for life, including a belief that God was in everything and made everything.
        Pantheism; Intelligent design (Teleology); Self-culture; audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00008.00003; Notowidigdo, Moekarto (Reel 5)
        Moekarto Notowidigdo, Foreign Minister of the Republic of Indonesia, describes being in jail during the Indonesian push for independence, and witnessing the comraderie of prisoners from all socioeconomic statuses, which led them to sing the Indonesian National Anthem during an execution.
        Self-determination, national; Brotherliness; Equality; Democracy; Social justice; Humanitarianism; Postcolonialism; International Relations; audio tape
      - Avoiding the Extremes of Life, MS025.005.004.005.00008.00004; Levy, David J. (Reel 5)
        David Levy, Deputy District Attorney of Contra Costa County in California, describes how he learned level-headed contentment in order to survive as a POW on the Death March of Bataan during WWII.
        Contentment; Happiness; Self-realization; Loyalty; Patriotism; Satisfaction; Optimism; audio tape
    - This I Believe, XTV18552, MS025.005.004.005.00009 (Reel 5)
      10" Reel. Job#116096. "French tape, side 2" written on back of box. No date is available for this reel.
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00009.00001; Tucker, Richard (Reel 5)
        Richard Tucker describes his belief in honesty and keeping one's word, and recounts how he strives to teach his son that even so-called "white lies" still hurt the teller of the lie.
        Judaism; Cantors (Judaism); Honesty; Truth; Responsibility; Character; Integrity; Sons; Moral Development; Ethics; Religious life; Courage; audio tape; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.)
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00009.00002; Dale, Henry H. (Henry Hallett) (Reel 5)
        Nobel Prize winning President of the Royal Academy, Henry Dale describes his belief in the "supreme value of truth" and the need for science to join forces with religion to help explain both material reality and our immaterial feelings of free will and a moral purpose in life.
        Purpose; Moral Conditions; Truth; Science; Materialism; Free will and determinism; Progress; Meaning (philosophy); audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00009.00003; Spry, Constance (Reel 5)
        Constance Spry describes how she adopted her father's love of truth, justice, beauty, and poetry, and explains her father's practice of listening to, rather than judging, the beliefs and opinions of others.
        Women social reformers; Social justice; Toleration; Truth; Beauty; Poetry; Floristry; audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00009.00004; Stegner, Wallace (Reel 5)
        Wallace Stegner describes his suspicions of "passionate faith" because of the religious intolerance it creates, and recounts his beliefs in virtues such as kindness and courage, and his belief that although consciences are developed differently, based on one's birthplace, nevertheless, people across the world share many values.
        Ethical relativism; Kindness; Courage; Religious tolerance; Responsibility; UncertaintyReligious aspects; audio tape
    - This I Believe, XTV18553, MS025.005.004.005.00010 (Reel 5)
      10" Reel. Job#116097. No date is available for this reel.
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00010.00001; Fuess, Claude Moore (Reel 5)
        Claude Fuess, Headmaster of Phillips Academy, describes himself as a "long-range optimist" who believes that the majority of today's boys are full of character and thoughtfulness, despite the newspaper headlines that suggest the moral decline of youth.
        Work; Character; Progress; Youth; Young men; Optimism; Teenagers; audio tape; Phillips Academy
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00010.00002; Liggett, Carr (Reel 5)
        Carr Liggett describes his belief that Jesus' Gospel is the way to happiness, and his uncertainities regarding the faith of his parents, as well as his beliefs in the importance of freedom, in accepting life and the world as we find it, and in tolerating and understanding others.
        Toleration; Compassion; Happiness; UncertaintyReligious aspects; Religious faith; Humility; Meaning (philosophy); audio tape; Carr Liggett Advertising
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00010.00003; Hurst, Fannie (Reel 5)
        Fannie Hurst talks about the example her husband set of how to live a selfless life, and her belief that many such lights of selfless living--though small--can together illuminate an entire arena in the world.
        Women novelists, American; Example; Altruism; audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00010.00004; Simon, John Allsebrook Simon, Viscount (Reel 5)
        Viscount Simon describes his belief that life is like a train which must come to an end at some point during the journey, but we should not view life with dread, even if he does not believe in an afterlife.
        Materialism; Death; Contentment; Avarice; audio tape
    - This I Believe, XTV18554, MS025.005.004.005.00011 (Reel 5)
      10" Reel. Job#116097. "1,2,3" written on reel. No date is available for this reel.
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00011.00001; Tobin, Emery (Reel 5)
        Emery Tobin, Editor and Founder of the Alaska Sportsman, describes his belief that people have been placed in a beautiful creation in order to work to improve themselves and to serve others.
        Nature; Beauty; Altruism; Purpose; Meaning (philosophy); Self-culture; audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00011.00002; Hurok, Sol (Reel 5)
        Sol Hurok recounts his experiences as an immigrant to America, and his vision for a venture that would bring classical artists to a popular audience.
        Immigrants; Art; Music; Self-actualization (Psychology); Optimism; Entrepreneurship; Music entrepreneurship; Performing artists; Theater; audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00011.00003; Katkov, Norman (Reel 5)
        Norman Katkov describes his belief in the internal struggle between good and evil and his belief that conscience will help a person to overcome that evil.
        Immigrants; Good and evil; Conscience; Hope; Optimism; Character; Moral Conditions; audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.005.00011.00004; Roosevelt, Theodore (Reel 5)
        Theodore Roosevelt III describes what he believes was an unusual family life growing up--his father ensured he spent time with the children--and describes his own belief in and appreciation for the support of his wife and the value of a strong home life.
        Families; Children; Fatherhood; Wives; Fathers and sons; Husbands; Marriage; audio tape; Montgomery, Scott and Company
    - This I Believe, XTV18555, MS025.005.004.006.00001 (Reel 6)
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00001.00001; Thayer, Eliza Talbott (Reel 6)
        Eliza Thayer observes how fortunate she has been in life to underscore her beliefs in the importance of love in one's life and why love assures her in the existence of life after death.
        Persistence; Faith; Love; Christianity; Afterlife; Prayer; Immaterialism; Social Networks; audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00001.00002; Wilson, Steuart (Reel 6)
        Steuart Wilson describes the search for truth and why a love for the truth must also be accompanied by the will to act on deeply felt convictions.
        Curiosity; Christianity; Golden rule; Truth; Responsibility; Love; Integrity; audio tape; Royal Opera House
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00001.00003; McKeen, John E. (Reel 6)
        John McKeen explains why beliefs are important and expresses his faith in the ultimate goodness of people, the intimate connection between the spiritual and the material, the drive to live, and the responsibility to safeguard the welfare of others and not only ourselves.
        Belief; Science; Optimism; Responsibility; Progress; Good and evil; audio tape; Charles Pfizer Co. of Brooklyn
      - To Preserve a Benevolent Attitude, MS025.005.004.006.00001.00004; Slater, Verona Wylie (Reel 6)
        Verona Slater describes her experience with religion as a child, the daughter of a minister, and how her beliefs in wisdom, kindess, courage and strneght have been shaped by these experiences.
        Wisdom; Fathers; Faith; Introspection; Christianity; Compassion; Mentoring; Gratitude; Courage; audio tape
    - This I Believe, XTV18556, MS025.005.004.006.00002 (Reel 6)
      10" Reel. Job#116097. "Save Reel 1" "WSC" "Save RI - Rev" written on reel. No date is available for this reel.
      - Attuning the Listening Ear, MS025.005.004.006.00002.00001; Taft, Charles P. (Reel 6)
        Charles Taft talks about God's love and the necessity to strive to be worthy of his love but understanding one's imperfections as well, and how he tries to connect the sublime with the more practical aspects of life through hard work and introspection.
        Christianity; Love; Respect for Persons; Courage; Work; Self-realization; Dignity; Pragmatism; audio tape
      - The Greatest of All Virtues, MS025.005.004.006.00002.00002; Woodcock, George (Reel 6)
        George Woodcock describes the expereinces he had growing up that led him to the belief in fairness and justice and also propelled him towards involvemnt in the labor movement.
        Justice; Equality; Progress; Struggle; Labor movement; Fairness; audio tape; British Trade Union Congress
      - Work Is the Sweetening of Life, MS025.005.004.006.00002.00003; Bottigheimer, Katherine Hoenig (Reel 6)
        Katherine Bottigheimer remembers an encounter with her elderly cousin Theresa and the consequent philosophy she unconsciously developed as a result: the value of hard work for the betterment of others.
        Families; Children; Utilitarianism; Responsibility; Civil rights; Labor movement; Work; audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00002.00004; Weinreb, Joseph (Reel 6)
        Joseph Weinreb reflects on ethics and morality and resolves that nothing is created bad or evil but becomes so Joseph Weinrab reflects on ethics and morality and resolves that nothing is created bad or evil but becomes so misdirection and love, compassion, and hard work are means by which we can achieve a harmonious world.
        Good and evil; Ethics; Self-culture; Introspection; Work; Compassion; Love; Peace; audio tape; Worcester Youth Guidance Center
    - This I Believe, XTV18561, MS025.005.004.006.00003 (Reel 6)
      10" Reel. Job#116098. No date is available for this reel.
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00003.00001; Hailsham of St. Marylebone, Quintin Hogg, Baron (Reel 6)
        Viscount Halisham considers and rejects the idea of materialism and embraces an immaterial universe at the center of which is Jesus Christ who can redeem the suffering and sins of mankind.
        Faith; Universe Immaterialism; Courage; Humanity; Jesus Christ; Suffering; audio tape; House of Lords (Tory Party)
      - Treasury of Hidden Virtues, MS025.005.004.006.00003.00002; Percy, Charles H. (Reel 6)
        Charles Percy explains why believes he has never met a person he did not respect, because he is open to listening and seeing who they truly are beneath the surface.
        Respect; Communication; Compassion; Optimism; Work; Humanity; Love; Responsibility; Interpersonal relations; Value; audio tape; Bell and Howell Co.; U.S. Navy
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00003.00003; Kemper, Lucrezia (Reel 6)
        Lucrezia Kemper describes how her family taught her the foundation of her beliefs and success; the value of faith in people, respect for others, kindness and generosity and security.
        Nature; Equality; Respect for Persons; Generosity; Families; Interpersonal relationships; Gratitude; Self-confidence; audio tape; Albert Frank-Gunther Law Advertising Agency
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00003.00004; McEwen, Robert Ward (Reel 6)
        Robert McEwen describes his faith in people that he developed from working with young people in education and his belief in the adaptability of people in a dynamic universe.
        Human beings; Optimism; Equality; Opportunity; Adaptation; Education; Young adults; Introspection; Change; Christianity; audio tape; Hamilton College; Presbyterian Church
    - This I Believe, XTV18562, MS025.005.004.006.00004 (Reel 6)
      10" Reel. Job#116098. "Incomplete Bl. Out" written on box. "1-2-3-4 5,6 8" written on reel. No date is available for this reel.
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00004.00001; Levenson, Harry (Reel 6)
        Harry Levenson relates his experience as a musician to the struggles of people in the world and explains his belief that doing ones best and appreciating the the individual as a perosn can guide us towards a peaceful future.
        Art; Music; Individualism; Creative ability; Struggle; Social Networks; Opportunity; Equality; Self-culture; Optimism; audio tape; Worcester Youth Orchestra
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00004.00002; Pillsbury, Philip W., Mrs. (Reel 6)
        Mrs. Pillsbury describes how she developed faith and belief in God and also her belief in the goodness of people and that we each have abilites they have been given to us for a purpose.
        Faith; Belief change; Human beings; Introspection; Humanitarianism; Social service; audio tape; Planned Parenthood of America
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00004.00003; Boothby, Robert John Graham, Baron (Reel 6)
        Robert Boothby discusses the incomprehensibility of life and the Universe and describes his efforts to improve society and life through politics and economics.
        Universe; Humility; Acquisitiveness; Humanitarianism; Politics; Economics.; Humanism; Individualism; Liberty; Humanity; audio tape; British Parliament
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00004.00004; Stevens, Lewis Miller (Reel 6)
        Lewis Stevens discusses the importance of the spirit, affection and faith in God's love to withstand the trials and calamity of the material world.
        Universe; Nature; Morality; Immaterialism; Love; Good and evil; Faith; audio tape; City Council of Philadelphia; Lincoln University
    - This I Believe, XTV18563, MS025.005.004.006.00005 (Reel 6)
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00005.00001; Bixler, Julius Seelye (Reel 6)
        Julius Bixler explores the tension between faith and reason and explains why skepticism falls short in comparrison to faith and experiences like love, friendship, family and the goodness of people.
        Love; Family; Reason; UncertaintyReligious aspects; Faith; Intuition; Questioning; Philosophy; Skepticism; Religion; audio tape; Colby College
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00005.00002; Heard, Gerald (Reel 6)
        Gerald Heard describes his perspectives on moral laws and the freedoms we must obtain to achieve true contentment in our life, free of fears and anxiety.
        Acquisitiveness; Progress; Morality; Liberty; Work; Fear; Aging; Death; Meaning (philosophy); Philosophy; audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00005.00003; Palmer, Paul, Mrs. (Reel 6)
        Mrs. Palmer describes the environment in which she grew up and the values and faith she acquired as a result, and why this faith might help others navigate through a confusing and "unpredictable era."
        Christianity; Childhood; Religious life; Faith; Prayer; Family; Civic improvement; Responsibility; America; Citizenship; audio tape; Farm Bureau
    - This I Believe, XTV18565, MS025.005.004.006.00006 (Reel 6)
      10" Reel. Job#116098. "TIB Reel 2-A" written on box, "2,4,5,6 8-3" written on reel. No date is available for this reel.
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00006.00001; Almy, Doris E. (Reel 6)
        Doris Almy explains how her trust in the omnipotence of God and the reestablishment of her faith allowed her to overcome her fears and anxiety, and discusses her belief in kindness and education as a relief from anxiety in the lives of others.
        Fear; Anxiety; Young adults; Education; Jesus Christ; Christianity; Harmony; Faith; Kindness; audio tape; League of Women Voters; Massachusetts Teachers' Federation
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00006.00002; Nottingham, Karl D. (Reel 6)
        Karl Nottingham explains our duty to adjust to society and some ways to do so such as; observing the Golden Rule, treating others with kindness, and helping those less fortunate, earning trust through friendship.
        Death; Nature; Fathers; Responsibility; Friendship; Trust; Golden rule; Kindness; Generosity; Christianity; Faith; audio tape; Indiana Legislature; Red Cross
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00006.00003; Cornelius, John C. (Reel 6)
        John Cornelius describes the two sayings that have stayed with him, "All things are great and small by comparison" and "service is the rent we pay for the space we occupy," and concludes by emphasizing the importance of supporting and educating youth to fight Communism.
        Communism; Social service; Struggle; Happiness; Self-actualization (Psychology); Education; Children; Relativity; audio tape
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00006.00004; Weiman, Elton Ewart "Tad" (Reel 6)
        E. E. Wieman explains the importance of sharing in life and how sharing is exemplified in sports; however, Wieman also describes how learned to share from his mother, which is the basis of his optimism.
        Young adults; Individualism; Education; Sharing; Sports; Mothers; Work; Interpersonal relations; Optimism; audio tape; University of Maine; University of Denver; United States Army
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.006.00006.00005; La Forge, Frank (Reel 6)
        Frank La Forge describes his work and achievements in his career as a musician and pianist and believes in the necessity of acting to the best of one's ability and faith in God's support of one's efforts.
        Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Planning; Music; Piano-Performance; Perfection; Faith; Purpose; Success; audio tape; New York Musicians' Club